Salvador Alvarado

1980 Gilly Ln, CONCORD, CA 94518 (925) 255-3530 salvador0807@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly motivated IT Professional with 3+ years of experience troubleshooting, upgrading, and maintain Networks and Computer systems. Strong Customer Service, Proficient with Widows Servers, DHCP, Active Directory, Ubuqity Wireless systems, SonicWALL An network infrastructure. looking for a role in IT where I can contribute my experience and training as well as continue to grow to become a better technician.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar. 2018 – Present Napa, Ca

Tier 2 Technician, Computer Engineering Group

- Deploy and maintain server infrastructure (Windows server 2008, 2012, 2016, and 2019)
- Manage Active Directory
- Perform Server upgrades (OS and Hardware)
- Perform Network Closet Cleanups (Cable management)
- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve hardware, software, or other network and system problems, and replace defective components when necessary.
- Coordinate with vendors for problem resolution.
- Install and configure wireless networking equipment.
 (Ubiquiti Equipment)
- Install new hardware or software systems or components, ensuring integration with existing network systems.
- Install or repair network cables.
- Provide telephone or on-site support related to networking or connectivity issues.
- Research hardware or software products to meet technical networking needs.
- Create or update technical documentation for network installations or changes to existing installations.
- Answer user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems.

Jul. 2014 – Mar. 2018 Benicia, California

computer service tech, Computer 1

- Check-in customers
- Provide Phone support
- Provide onsite support as requested
- Troubleshoot and repair computer problems
- Assist with Server troubleshooting
- Assist with network troubleshooting
- Troubleshoot computer hardware (replace if need it)
- Troubleshoot and repair printers issues
- Keep inventory of parts
- Order of inventory
- Keep track of repairs
- Invoice customers
- Customer follow up
- Arrange for disposal of E-west
- Maintaining work area clean

Feb. 2013 – Jun. 2014 Martinez, California

Computer Tech, Graceful Tech

- Customer service (Answering the Phones, Intake computer for repairs, calling Customers when repairs were done)
- Delivery computers or parts
- Phone support and on-site support if required for residential Customers
- Troubleshoot and repair computer problems
- Repair computer hardware
- Work with other technicians to ensure that repair is done on time and keep the customer informed
- Keep track of inventory
- · Keep work area clean

EDUCATION

Information Technology, Electronics

• DVC - Pleasant Hill, CA

Aug. 2008

High School Diploma: Electronics

• CECYTE - Jimenez, Michoacán

SKILLS

Team Pleayer

Office Suite (Word, Excel, Power point, Outlook, Sharepoint, OneDrive , Teams)
Active Directory
DNS
DHCP
Communication
Project Managment
Costumer service
Perform under Pressure
Fast learning